<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Parameters</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Parameters">
      <subsection name="Description">
        <p>Parameter set is an abstraction very often encountered in application development. Here
        is an attempt to define it's characteristics:</p>
        <p>
          <ol>
            <li>A set is composed of named parameters.</li>
            <li>A subset of parameters that share a common name prefix can be viewed as a nested
              parameter set.</li>
            <li>Parameter values are primarily represented as strings
              <ol>
                <li>Parameter values may be retrieved as instances of several Java primitive types, or
                  arrays thereof. At least following types need to be supported:
                  <ul>
                    <li>String</li>
                    <li>boolean</li>
                    <li>int</li>
                    <li>long</li>
                    <li>float</li>
                  </ul>
                </li>
                <li>A NumberFormatException will be thrown by the numeric value retrieval methods if the 
                  value is not a correct number representation.</li>
              </ol>
            </li>
            <li>Parameter may have more than one value.
              <ol>
                <li>Multiple values of a paremeter are ',' separated.</li>
                <li>',' characters inside parameter values must be '\' escaped.</li>
                <li>The values of the parameter are returned in the same order that they are 
                  defined.</li>
                <li>Different methods are used to retrieve a single value and all values of the 
                  parameter. If one value is expected, but multiple are available, an unchecked 
                  exception will be thrown.</li>
              </ol>
            </li>
            <li>A default value may be provided upon retrieval of the parameter value. If the set
              does not contain a value of the parameter the provided default will be returned.</li>
            <li>If no default value is provided and the set does not contain parameter value, an 
              unchecked exception will be thrown.</li>
            <li>The parameter set must be serializable as a human readable/editable string, 
              and deserializable from that representation.
              <ol>
                <li>A parameter is represented as &lt;name&gt; '=' &lt;values&gt; pairs.</li>
                <li>Parameters withing a set are newline separater. Thus newline characters in
                parameter values need to be '\' escaped.</li>
                <li>Any characters outside the 7 bit US-ASCII range must be escaped using Java
                Unicode sequences when generating the string representation. Both escape
                sequences and Unicode characters must be accepted when parsing.</li>
              </ol>
            </li>
          </ol>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Browse">
        <p>
          <ul>
            <li>Parameters <a href="../apidocs/org/objectledge/parameters/Parameters.html">JavaDoc</a></li>
            <li>Parameters <a href="../xref/org/objectledge/parameters/Parameters.html">XRef</a></li>
            <li>Parameters <a href="http://objectledge.org/viewcvs.cgi/ledge-components/src/main/java/org/objectledge/parameters/Parameters.java">CVS log</a></li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Implementations">
        <p>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <p>DefaultParamteres is a transient, memory based implementation of <code>Parameters</code>
              interface.</p>
              <p class="more"><a href="parameters/DefaultParameters.html">more</a></p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>DBParamteres is a persistent, database based implementation of <code>Parameters</code>
              interface.</p>
              <p class="more"><a href="parameters/DBParameters.html">more</a></p>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
