<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <body>
    <release version="0.2" date="January 29, 2004">
      <action dev="fil" type="update">
        New format was introduced for component/subsystem documentation, with 
        obligatory "Description" and "Browse" sections (the latter with links to
        JavaDoc, XRef &amp; CVS log) and "Dependencies" (components/jars). "Constructor
        parameters" section is given for every IoC 3 component. Other sections are 
        included as necessary, and links to config schemata, and example files 
        (through cvsview) are added to "Browse" section where applicable.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update">
        <code>FileSystemProvider</code> implementations were moved to <code>org.objectledge.filesystem</code>
        package, as they are accessed by the casual users - they should not be forced to look into impl packages.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update">
        <code>FileSystem.getResource(String)</code> method returns now actual URL pointing
        to the found files, as returned by the providers. These URLs can be safely serialized
        as Strings, and deserialized in any context. This allows using them as InputSource
        systemIds, with correct semantics.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update">
        <code>XMLValidator</code> API was changed so that it accepts URLs not FS paths.
        This makes XMLValidator independent of FileService, but retaining the functionality,
        thanks to <code>FileService.getResource()</code> method.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="fix">
        XMLValidator is now compatible with Crimson and Xerces parsers, Saxon is not 
        required any longer.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update">
        <code>FileSystemProvider</code> implementations were moved to <code>org.objectledge.filesystem</code>
        package, as they are accessed by the casual users - they should not be forced to look into impl packages.
      </action>
    </release>
    <!-- type = add fix remove update -->
    <release version="0.3" date="September 3, 2004">
      <action dev="pablo" type="add" issue="LEDGE-1">
        More tests for Filesystem has been written.
      </action>
      <action dev="pablo" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-3">
        Multiple character blocks with a single tag are now handled correctly by i18n xml loader.
      </action>
      <action dev="pablo" type="add" issue="LEDGE-7">
        More tests for StringUtils have been written.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-8">
        Test for ErrorHandlingPipeline have been improved.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-9">
        Test for ContextToolFactory have been improved.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-16">
        FileAppender and RollingFileAppender implementations working over Ledge FS are now available.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-17">
        LoggingConfigurator has been enhanced to pico-instantiate certain Log4J components, making
        components in Ledge container available for their initializaiton.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-18">
        Ledge was updated to compile against pico 1.0-beta-4 (superceded by later changes)
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-24">
        Quirsk in commandline processing were removed thanks to migration to commons-cli.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="remove" issue="LEDGE-31">
        LedgeServletTest.testLedgeServlet2 testcase was removed, because of it was causing problems,
        and was essentialy an integration and not unit test.
      </action>
      <action dev="pablo" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-41">
        uploadLimit property was moved to the proper place - FileUpload configuration.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-43">
        HttpContext was briefly documented.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-45">
        Ledge web documentation was reorganized.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-48">
        ThreadPool was implemented using commons-pool.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-51">
        Tests for policy package were added.
      </action>
      <action dev="pablo" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-52">
        Strings can be now defined outside of any prefix defined inside i18m xml file - prefix
        defined by file name applies to those.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-58">
        Build system was upgraded to use pre-1.0 maven.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-59">
        Stack trace formatter was ported in, and adapted to use JDK1.4+ features.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-60">
        Stack trace prettyprinting was added to PrintExceptionValve and ExceptionReriderctorValve.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-61">
        Stack trace prettyprinting was plugged into Ledge's Log4J loggers.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-62">
        ConfigurationFactory was moved into ledge-components module. It's needed by some components
        and it's useful in component tests.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-63">
        ConfigurationFactory was split into part handling configuration loading, and part hanling
        associating configuration with components.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-64">
        LoggingConfigurator was moved into ledge-components module. A component may depend on it
        to request that logging be initialized before the component is constructed. Useful if 
        instantiating the component causes massive logging from dependant 3rd party objects.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-65">
        ledge.root system property is no longer needed for tests
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-66">
        TestSuite classes were removed. Test are looked up easily withouthem both by Maven and Eclipse.
      </action>
      <action dev="pablo" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-67">
        DatabaseContext was fixed to create subcontexts with correct ids.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="add" issue="LEDGE-68">
        Unicode characters are correctly passed around int POST and GET requests, and links are 
        generated encoded aproprietly.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="update" issue="LEDGE-69">
        All Java and Velocity source files were transcoded into UTF-8, and apropriate settings were
        applied for the build system and Eclipse.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="add" issue="LEDGE-70">
        HTML entities sent by the browser are decoded into unicode characters in parameters.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="add" issue="LEDGE-71">
        Unicode characters not mappable to the chosen output encoding are transformed into HTML
        entities.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-72">
        Table filters are now stored in the tool not the state objects. Fixes problems with temporary
        momory leakage.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-73">
        LinkTool uses custom url encoder to avoid encoding / in the query string.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-74">
        LinkTool was stripped from unsed code reorganized for better maintainablitiy.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-75">
        I18n strings can be defined in intermediate nodes in addition to leaf nodes.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-76">
        All old issues were scheduled among releases.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-77">
        Table toolkit parmeters were changed into camelCase.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-79">
       LinkTool was fixed with respect to extensibility.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-80">
       I18n tool was fixed with respect to extensibility.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-81">
        SecuirtyHelper is no longer refernced statically, allowing more flexibility and extensibility.
      </action>
      <action dev="zwierzem" type="fix" issue="LEDGE-82">
        I18n context border cases were worked out.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="add" issue="LEDGE-86">
        New roadmap document was prepared.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-87">
        Jira house cleaning was performed including setting components and versions on all issues,
        closing resolved issues and sheduling issues among releases.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-88">
        Dev version docs were generated with Maven 1.0 with some adjustments and published on the web.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-94">
        Maven release management tools were used to do the release for the first time.
      </action>
      <action dev="fil" type="update" issue="LEDGE-95">
        changes.xml files were reorganized and filled in from jira.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>