<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>ObjectLedge</title>
  </properties>
    
  <body>
    <section name="Introduction">
      <p>
        Object Ledge is a platform for building applications in Java 2 Standard and Enterprise 
        Edition environments. 
      </p>
      <p>
        ObjectLedge follows component / container and Inversion Of Control design paradigms 
        implemented with the excelent <a href="http://picocontainer.org">PicoContainer</a> package.
      </p>
      <p>
        ObjectLedge provides a number of components - basic building blocks of the applications,
        a few extensions to the Pico framework, customized containers for easy deployment of
        applications in command line, daemon, and J2EE servlet environments.
      </p>

      <subsection name="Why the name?">
        <p>
          "Webster's Revised Unabridged Dictionary (1913)"<br/>
          <b><u>Ledge</u></b> <i>Ledge</i> (le^j), n. <i>Akin</i> to AS. licgan to lie, Icel.<br/>
          liggja; cf. Icel. l"<i>o</i>gg the ledge or rim at the bottom of a<br/>
          cask. See <i>Lie</i> to be prostrate. <i>Formerly</i> written <i>lidge</i>.
        </p>
        <ol>
         <li> 
           A shelf on which articles may be laid; also, that which <br/>
           resembles such a shelf in form or use, as a projecting <br/>
           ridge or part, or a molding or edge in joinery.
         </li>
 
         <li>A shelf, ridge, or reef, of rocks.</li>
 
         <li>
           A layer or stratum. 
           <blockquote>
             The lowest ledge or row should be of stone. <br/> 
             -- Sir H. Wotton.
           </blockquote>
          </li>

         <li>
           (Mining) A lode; a limited mass of rock bearing valuable <br/> 
           mineral.
         </li>
    
         <li>
           (Shipbuilding) A piece of timber to support the deck, <br/> 
           placed athwartship between beams.
         </li>
        </ol>
        <p>
          We hope that Object Ledge will be a rock-solid foundation on which a variety of 
          aplications can be built easily and quickly, with confidence into the platform's
          integrity.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="License">
       <p>
        <a href="http://opensource.org/docs/certification_mark.php">
          <img style="border:none; float:left; margin-right:10px;" src="http://opensource.org/graphics/osi-certified-120x100.png"/>
        </a>
        <b>This software is OSI Certified Open Source Software.<br/>
        OSI Certified is a certification mark of the Open Source Initiative.</b><br/>
        <br/>
        Object Ledge is made available on the terms of BSD <a href="license.html">license</a>,
        which has been certified by the <a href="http://opensource.org">Open Source Initiative</a>
        organization.<br/>
        <br/>
        In short, you are granted the right to use Object Ledge in any endevaour commercial,
        or not, and create derived works, as long as you give apropriate credit to the authors.
       </p>
      </subsection>
      
    </section>
    
    </body>
</document>
  
