<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Related projects</title>
  </properties>
  
  <body>
    <section name="Related projects">
      <subsection name="Coral">
        <p><a href="http://coral.objectledge.org">Coral</a></p>
        <p>Coral is as an object oriented database. It manages structured resources, that 
        can be mapped to Java objects in a JDBC relational database. </p>
        <p>Besides simple object persistency mechanism Coral provides an expressive security system, 
        many kinds of resources relations (intrinsic tree organization or resources, 
        reference attributes, set theory relations) and a powerful query facility that 
        can use attribute values and resource relations to select objects from the 
        store.</p>
        <p>The resources can be manipulated through Java API, or interactively using
        RML script language. Resource types can be created and modified at runtime 
        (existing resource instances are aproprietly adjusted). Java wrapper sources for
        the resources can be genereated using a Maven plugin from RML scripts, or a live
        database instance. Datatype schemata and security information can be exported
        to RML scripts, and resources can be imported/exported using XML.</p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Cyklotron">
        <p>
          <a href="http://cyklotron.org">Cyklotron</a>
        </p>
        <p>Cyklotron is a content management system - an application for easy development and 
        management of websites. </p>
        <p> Cyklotron project is sponsored by major player in the Non Governmental Organizations 
        domain, and thus it's primary focus is serving the needs of NGOs, but the developed software 
        will be also useful and available for commercial entities.</p>
        <p>Cyklotron is based on earlier CykloKlon project. You can see Cyklotron in 
        action on these major NGO websites in Poland: 
        <a href="http://www.ngo.pl">http://www.ngo.pl</a> and 
        <a href="http://www.niepelnosprawni.info">http://www.niepelnosprawni.info</a>. The aim of 
        this project is creating a next generation of Cyklotron software, that is faster more robust
        and easier to use, and providing it to the wide public.</p>
        <p>It is developed as an Open Source project, and is based on a large number of open source 
        libraries and tools. The software developed in the course of the project will be available 
        for any non-commercial or commercial use on the terms of liberal BSD license.</p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Cyklotron 2">
        <p>
          <a href="http://cykotron2.cyklotron.org">Cyklotron 2</a>
        </p>
    		<p>Cyklotron 2 is the successor of Cyklotron content management system.</p>
		<p>Cyklotron 2 is a cleanroom reimplementation, that focuses on simplicity of the internal
		mechanisms, and extensibility of the system by adding custom applications.</p>
		<p>The focal point of Cyklotron2 is the Dashboard - the common administrative interface
		for all embedded applications, that integrates tree view of all resources in the system
		accessible to the user, dynamic properties pane and context sensitive operations menu.
		All these elements are metadata driven, and new applications can easily integrate into
		this framework through a number of well defined extension points.</p>
		<p>Cyklotron 2 offers a pervasive security system. Applications define roles and permissions
		specific to their problem domain, and their assignment to particular resources, groups, and
		individuals is managed in a consistent way across the whole system.</p>
		<p>Public (as opposed to administrative) interface of Cyklotron 2 is similar to that developed
		in Cyklotron. It is based on layout styles, layout templates, component slots (sockets)
		and components. Custom applications can extend the interface by providing custom components
		that are subject to configuration, visual customization and internationalization through
		shared, consistent mechanisms.</p>
		<p>At this point only a fraction of Cyklotron functionality was ported. The current objective
		of the project is to produce a set of applications sufficient to use Cyklotron 2 as a 
		group collaboration system similar to <a href="http://groups.engo.pl">eNGO groups</a>.</p>
      </subsection>      
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
