<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Overview of Pico extensions</title>
  </properties>
  
  <body>
    <section name="PicoContainer extensions">
      <subsection name="SequenceParameter">
        <p>Allows hinting the component's constructor arguments of aggregated types. Both Java
        arrays and java.util.Collection objects are supported. The elements of the sequence are
        <code>org.picocontainer.Parameter</code> objects - they may resolve to constants,
        component references, or nested sequences.
        </p>
		<p class="more"><a href="SequenceParameter.html">more</a></p>
	  </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Component customization">
        <p>This mechanism introduces a concept of customized (polymorphic) components. When a 
        customized component is requested during instantiation of a target component, a provider
        class is asked for an actual object instance, depending on the target component's key and
        implementation class.
        </p>
        <p>To use this mechanism, you need to use CustmomizingConstructorComponentAdapter instead of
        ConstructorComponentAdapter for instantiating your compoments. Additionally you need to
        register CustomizedComponentAdapter for each of the components you want polymorphic, using
        apropriate CustomizedComponentProvider objects.
        </p>
		<p class="more"><a href="ComponentCustomization.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Enhanced XmlFrontEnd">
        <p>Ledge XmlFrontEnd has the same functionality as the Nano-provided one but with a few 
        changes and additions.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>ComponentAdapterFactory may be declared for the top level container</li>
          <li>ComponentAdapterFactory may be declared using tags, with nesting 
            (DecoratingComponentAdapterFactoryPatern)</li>
          <li>for both components and component-parameters, both string and class keys may be used</li>
          <li><a href="SequenceParameter.html">SeuqenceParameters</a> are supported</li>
          <li>The composition is checked against a RelaxNG schema.</li>
        </ul>
		<p class="more"><a href="XmlFrontEnd.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
  