<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Overview of components</title>
  </properties>
  
  <body>
    <section name="Components">
      <subsection name="FileSystem">
        <p>FileSystem component provides a set of operations that are performed on files, directories
        and abstract pathnames, including: file reading, writing (streams, byte[], String), random 
        access (read, write, rewinding), atomic creation, deletion and renaming; directory creation, 
        deletion, renaming and listings; path name normalisation and basename / directory name 
        splitting and creation of java.net.URL objects that can be used to access the component's
        functionality.</p>

		<p class="more"><a href="FileSystem.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection> 
      
      <subsection name="XMLValidator">
        <p>The primary schema language used throughout ObjectLedge project is RelaxNG, but the Jing
        library determines the schema languague using XML namespace of the top level element. At the
        moment XML based schema languages supported by Jing and thus by XMLValidator are W3C XSD, 
        Scheamtron and Namespace Routing Language.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="XMLValidator.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Context">
        <p>Provides dependant components with a nontion of <em>thread context</em>, that is a set
		of name - value pairs (boths elements are arbitrary Java objectss) that is specific
		to the currently executing thread. This allows passing information across the method
		call stack without actually pushing it through formal arguments. Servlet Request and
		Response objects, authentication and transactiotion managment objects are conveniently
		passed around using thread context.</p>

		<p class="more"><a href="Context.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Pipeline">
        <p>A pipeline component can be considered a composite <code>java.lang.Runnable</code>
        implementation. It delegates the invocation of it's <code>run()</code> to a number of
        dependant components called <em>Valves</em>. The "units of work" are passed between the
        Valves using thread <a href="Context.html">Context</a>.</p>
        <p class="more"><a href="Pipeline.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="I18n">
        <p>I18n component provides the access to the locale sensitive <code>String</code> resources.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="I18n.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="VelocityTemplating">
        <p>Provides the simple templating based on velocity engine.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="VelocityTemplating.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="MailSystem">
        <p>Manages the mail sessions and allows to prepare and send email messages.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="MailSystem.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="ContextFactory">
        <p>This component provides a registry of JNDI naming and directory context.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="ContextFactory.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>

	  <subsection name="ThreadPool">
	    <p>Executes <em>Tasks</em> asynchronously, using long running daemon threads, or 
	    using worker threads from a pool of limited capacity.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="ThreadPool.html">more</a></p>
	  </subsection>

      <subsection name="Scheduler">
        <p>The scheduler component manages the jobs that starts at specified points of time.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="Scheduler.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>      

      <subsection name="EventSystem">
        <p>Provides a common facility for associating event generators with receivers.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="EventSystem.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>     

	  <subsection name="Database">
        <p>A convenience wrapper around database related components.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="Database.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>     
          
	  <subsection name="Persistence">
        <p>The persistence component provides simple Object-Relational Database mapping.</p>
		<p class="more"><a href="Persistence.html">more</a></p>
      </subsection>           
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
  
